Guide to the Robert Abercrombie Lovett Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence and Topical Files, 1919-1986; Series I; 12.25' (30 boxes)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: congratulatory messages on retirement as assistant secretary of war for air, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 226)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: congratulatory messages on retirement as under secretary of state, 1948-1949 (Box 17, Folder 227)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: financial record, 1923, 1946, 1949, 1950-1956, 1960, 1970, 1972, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 228)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: medals, undated (Box 18, Folder 229)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: medical records, 1933, 1937,1947-1949, 1952-1956, 1959, 1967, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 230-231)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: memorabilia, miscellaneous, 1949-1950, 1980, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 232)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: newspaper and magazine clippings, 1940, 1948-1952, 1960, 1965, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 233)
    See also: box 34, folder 474
  - Lovett, Robert A.: ninetieth birthday, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 234)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: notes, 1961-1963, undated (Box 18, Folder 235)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: passports, 1925, 1927, 1928, 1932, 1955, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 236)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: photographs, 1937, 1949, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 237)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: photographs and portraits, 1952, 1964, 1971, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 238)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: photographs and portraits, undated (Box 18, Folder 239)
  - Lovett, Robert Scott: biographies, 1932-1936, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 240)
  - Lovett, Robert Scott: correspondence concerning portrait of Col. Abercrombie for Estill Library, 1932 (Box 19, Folder 241)
  - Lovett, Robert Scott: messages of condolence on his death, 1932 June-1933, undated (Box 19, Folder 242-244)
  - Lovett, Robert Scott: minutes in memory, 1932, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 245)
  - Lovett, Robert Scott: newspaper clippings, 1932, undated (Box 19, Folder 246)
  - Lovett, Robert Scott: photographs, undated (Box 19, Folder 247)
  - Lovett Cemetery, 1958-1972, 1977-1982 (Box 19, Folder 248)
  - Lovett family: genealogy, 1934-1936, 1949-1967, undated (Box 19, Folder 249)
  - Lovett family: selected correspondence, 1976-1982 (Box 19, Folder 249a)
  - Lubin, Isador, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 250)
  - Luckman, Charles, 1953-1958 (Box 19, Folder 251)
  - Lunch Club, 1930 (Box 19, Folder 252)
  - Lyon, Cecil, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 253)
  - Mac (Box 20, Folder 254)
  - Mae-Me (Box 20, Folder 255)
  - Mi-My (Box 20, Folder 256)
  - McCarthy, Frank, 1955-1959, 1980-1983 (Box 20, Folder 257)
  - McCloy, John J., 1960-1963, 1965-1971 (Box 20, Folder 258-259)
  - McCloy, John J., 1972-1985, undated (Box 20, Folder 260)
  - McCrary, John Reagan, 1954-1963 (Box 20, Folder 261)
  - McLean, Joseph, 1963, 1968, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 262)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1928, 1933-1943, 1949, 1953, 1959-1972 (Box 20, Folder 263)
  - MacLeish, William H., 1972-1974 (Box 20, Folder 264)
  - Madden, John B., 1981-1985 (Box 20, Folder 265)
  - Mark Twain Journal, 1970-1972 (Box 20, Folder 266)
  - Marshall, George C., 1944-1958 (Box 20, Folder 267)
  - Marshall, George C.: honors, memorials, etc., 1950, 1955-1966 (Box 21, Folder 268)
  - Marshall, Katherine, 1959-1960 (Box 21, Folder 269)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Corporation, 1953, 1966, 1977, 1981-1984 (Box 21, Folder 270)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Corporation, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 271)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Visiting Committee for the Center for International Studies, 1956-1968 (Box 21, Folder 272-276)
  - Menzies, Sir Robert Gordon, 1967, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 277)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1940, 1949-1950, 1965-1966, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 278)
  - Meyer, Eugene, 1955-1956 (Box 21, Folder 279)
  - Miller, Melville B., 1974-1976 (Box 21, Folder 280)
  - Millhiser, Ross R., 1984-1985 (Box 21, Folder 281)
  - Mitchell, William, 1956-1962 (Box 21, Folder 282)
  - Moral Re-Armament, 1961, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 283)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Company, 1959, 1963, 1965-1966, 1967-1968 (Box 22, Folder 284-285)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1969-1971 (Box 22, Folder 286-287)
  - Moseley, Nicolas, 1966-1969 (Box 22, Folder 288)
  - Murphy, Charles J., 1960, 1981-1983 (Box 22, Folder 289)
  - N (Box 22, Folder 290)
  - National Aeronautic Association of U.S.A., 1928-1940, 1947 (Box 22, Folder 291)
    See also: box 28, folder 385
  - National Foreign Trade Council, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 292)
  - National Fund for Medical Education, 1949-1950, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 293)
  - National Institute of Social Sciences, 1941-1946, 1952, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 294)
  - National Science Foundation, 1957-1963 (Box 22, Folder 295)
  - National security policy, Vietnam War, and federal budget, 1965 February-1966, undated (Box 22, Folder 296-297)
  - National War College, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 298)
  - Naval Aviation Museum Foundation, 1966, 1975, 1981-1985 (Box 23, Folder 299)
  - Navy League of the United States, 1967-1969, 1976-1979 (Box 23, Folder 300)
  - New York Life Insurance Company, 1949-1961, 1968-1971 (Box 23, Folder 301)
  - Newcomen Society, 1949, 1962, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 302)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1971-1972 (Box 23, Folder 303)
  - Norstad, Lauris, 1950, 1962-1966 (Box 23, Folder 304)
  - Norstad, Lauris, invitations to luncheon in his honor: A-N, 1962 December-1963 January (Box 23, Folder 305)
  - Norstad, Lauris, invitations to luncheon in his honor: P-W, 1962 December-1963 January (Box 23, Folder 306)
  - O (Box 23, Folder 307)
  - O'Brien, William G., 1953, 1965, 1980-1984 (Box 23, Folder 308)
  - O'Hara, John, 1956-1968, 1970, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 309)
  - Oldfield, Barney, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 310)
  - Osborne, John, 1961-1964 (Box 23, Folder 311)
  - Overseas Press Club of America, 1949, 1953-1954 (Box 23, Folder 312)
  - Pa-Pi (Box 23, Folder 313)
  - Pl-Pu (Box 23, Folder 314)
  - Pace, Frank, 1953-1960 (Box 24, Folder 315)
  - Patterson, Robert P., 1940, 1945, 1950-1952 (Box 24, Folder 316)
  - Patterson, Robert P.: memorials, 1952-1960, 1965-1969 (Box 24, Folder 317)
  - Pawley, William D., 1953-1962 (Box 24, Folder 318)
  - Petersen, Howard C., 1961, 1980, 1984-1985 (Box 24, Folder 319)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Associates, 1963, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 320)
  - Photograph requests, 1949-1950 (Box 24, Folder 321)
  - Pinchot, Cornelia Bryce, 1953, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 322)
  - "Pleasance": home of Robert and Adele Lovett, 1963, 1975, undated (Box 24, Folder 323)
  - Pogue, Forrest C., 1975-1976, 1981, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 324)
  - Presidential Medal of Freedom, 1963-1964 (Box 24, Folder 326)
  - Price, Don K., 1977 (Box 24, Folder 327)
  - Princeton University, 1946, 1959-1963 (Box 24, Folder 328)
  - Princeton University: honorary degree, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 329)
    See also:box 34, folder 472
  - Princeton University. John Foster Dulles Library and Oral History Project, 1959-1968 (Box 24, Folder 330)
  - Public administration and management, 1944-1946 (Box 25, Folder 331)
  - Puryear, Edgar F., 1977-1978 (Box 25, Folder 332)
  - Q (Box 25, Folder 333)
  - Ra-Roo (Box 25, Folder 334)
    - Politicians: requests from and contributions to, 1933, 1951, 1954, 1956, 1960, 1962-1971, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 325)
  - Ros-Ru (Box 25, Folder 335)
  - Randall, Carey A., 1955, 1959, 1960, 1962-1965, 1974-1975 (Box 25, Folder 336)
  - Research Institute of America, 1960-1962, 1966-1967 (Box 25, Folder 337)
  - Richardson, Stanton, 1965-1966 (Box 25, Folder 338)
  - Ridgway, Matthew B., 1951, 1959, 1963, 1971, 1973, 1975-1976, 1979-1980, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 339)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1949-1963, undated (Box 25, Folder 340)
  - Rockefeller Foundation. Investment Advisory Service, 1960-1961, undated (Box 25, Folder 341)
  - Roeslen, Rudolf, 1933 (Box 25, Folder 342)
  - Rosenberg, Anna M., 1953-1955, 1957-1958, 1964, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 343)
  - Rosenberg, Jerry P., 1948, 1975-1976 (Box 25, Folder 344)
  - Rosenman, Samuel I., 1958-1959 (Box 25, Folder 345)
  - Rowny, Edward L., 1978 (Box 25, Folder 346)
  - Royal Horticultural Society, 1972-1983 (Box 25, Folder 347)
  - Rusk, Dean, 1960-1962, 1969, 1978, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 348)
    See also: box 10, folder 110
  - Sa-Si (Box 26, Folder 349)
  - Sm-Sy (Box 26, Folder 350)
  - Sachs, Alexander, 1939, 1950, 1958, 1961, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 351)
  - Saltzman, Charles E., 1970, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 352)
  - Salveron, Anastacia; Salveron, Francisco J.; Salveron, Robert Lovett, 1956, 1961-1982, undated (Box 26, Folder 353-354)
  - Sam Houston State Teachers College: honorary degree, 1952 (Box 26, Folder 355-355a)
  - Sam Rayburn Foundation and Library, 1962-1972 (Box 26, Folder 356)
  - Sand, William, 1970-1972 (Box 26, Folder 357)
  - Schilling, Jessie, 1979-1980 (Box 26, Folder 358)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M., 1967, 1977, 1981-1983 (Box 26, Folder 359)
  - Schreiver, B. A., 1963, 1965-1966 (Box 26, Folder 360)
  - Seibert, Donald A., 1964 (Box 26, Folder 361)
  - Sellers, Robert C., 1962, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 362)
  - Sherwood, Madeline, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 363)
  - Silvercuys, Baron Robert, 1950, 1953-1954, 1958-1960, 1965, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 364)
  - Slater, Nelson, 1961-1965 (Box 26, Folder 365)
  - Smith, Cyrus R., 1945, 1978-1979 (Box 26, Folder 366)
  - Sorenson, Theodore C., 1966 (Box 27, Folder 367)
  - Spencer, William, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 368)
  - Sprague, Robert C., 1958 (Box 27, Folder 369)
  - State Bar Association of Texas, 1952-1955 (Box 27, Folder 370)
  - Steelman, John R., 1953, 1959-1965 (Box 27, Folder 371)
  - Stewart, Donald Ogden, 1931, 1943, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 372)
  - Stohl, Ralph N., 1960-1965 (Box 27, Folder 373)
  - Strauss, Lewis, 1953-1954, 1958, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 374)
  - Sylvanus Thayer Award, 1950, 1960-1967 (Box 27, Folder 375)
  - Sylvanus Thayer Award, 1968-1974, 1980-1984, undated (Box 27, Folder 376)
  - Sylvanus Thayer Award: congratulatory messages, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 377)
  - T (Box 27, Folder 378)
  - Tannenwald, Ted, 1953-1957, 1961, 1964-1966 (Box 27, Folder 379)
  - Taxes, spending, budget, 1939, 1940 (Box 27, Folder 380)
  - Texaco, 1960-1964 (Box 27, Folder 381)
  - Texas National Bank, 1925-1942, 1950, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 382-383)
  - Thompson, Kenneth, 1978-1979, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 384)
  - Thompson Speed Trophy, 1926-1933 (Box 28, Folder 385)
  - Thornton, Charles B., 1946, 1949, 1953-1954, 1963-1965, 1978-1981 (Box 28, Folder 386)
    See also: box 16, folder 217
  - Truman, Harry S., 1945, 1953-1965, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 387)
  - Truman, Harry S.: birthday celebrations, 1954-1967 (Box 28, Folder 388)
  - Truman, Harry S.: memorials, etc., 1959, 1964-1973 (Box 28, Folder 389)
  - Tufts University, 1974, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 390)
  - Union Bank of Switzerland, 1958, 1962-1963 (Box 28, Folder 391)
  - Union Pacific, 1970, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 392)
  - Union Pacific: R.A.L's retirement, 1940, 1966-1967 (Box 28, Folder 393-394)
  - United Aircraft Corporation, 1963-1966 (Box 28, Folder 395)
  - United States. Blue Ribbon Defense Panel, 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 396)
  - United States. Naval Reserve, 1924-1928 (Box 28, Folder 397)
  - United States. War Department, 1942-1943, undated (Box 28, Folder 398)
  - United States Military Academy, undated (Box 28, Folder 399)
    See also: box 27, folder 376
  - United States Naval Institute, 1939, 1941, 1949 (Box 28, Folder 400)
  - V (Box 28, Folder 401)
  - Van Bellinghen, Carlos, 1959-1960, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 402)
  - Van Kleffens, Eelco, 1949-1950, 1956-1958, 1960-1961, 1967, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 403)
  - Vandenberg, Arthur H., 1949, 1951, 1954, 1967-1968 (Box 28, Folder 404)
  - Vorys, John M., 1927, 1933-1940, 1949, 1958-1965 (Box 28, Folder 405)
  - Wa-Wh (Box 28, Folder 406)
  - Wi-Wy (Box 29, Folder 407)
  - Wallenburg, Marcus, Sr.; Wallenburg, Marcus, Jr., 1935-1936, 1946-1962, 1963-1973 (Box 29, Folder 408-409)
  - Wallenburg, Marcus, Sr., 1974-1982 (Box 29, Folder 410-411)
  - Watson, Thomas J., 1978-1979, 1982, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 412)
  - Wilcox, Francis O., 1955, 1968-1971 (Box 29, Folder 413)
  - Wilkinson, Harvie, Jr., 1961-1964, 1966, 1971, 1980-1981 (Box 29, Folder 414)
  - Williams, Langbourne M., 1957-1985 (Box 29, Folder 415-416)
  - Williams College: honorary degree, 1950-1951 (Box 29, Folder 417)
  - Winn, Reginald, 1969-1970, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 418)
  - Winnacker, Rudolf A., 1970-1973 (Box 29, Folder 419)
    See also:box 27, folder 376
    See also: box 32, folder 447
  - Wolfe, K. B., 1960 (Box 29, Folder 420)
  - Wooley, Knight, 1967, 1974, 1981, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 421)
  - Y (Box 29, Folder 422)
  - Yale University: honorary degree, 1952 (Box 29, Folder 423)
  - Yale University. Class of 1918, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 424)
  - Z (Box 29, Folder 425)
  - Zobrist, Benedict, 1971-1972 (Box 29, Folder 426)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 30, Folder 427)
- Writings, 1936-1981; Series II; 1.25' (3 boxes)
  The material in this series is arranged in chronological order.
  - "Condensed Summary Tables", 1936 (Box 31, Folder 428)
  - "Gilt-Edged Insecurity", 1937 (Box 31, Folder 429)
  - "European Outlook - If Any", 1939 (Box 31, Folder 430)
  - "Dupe's Disease", 1939 (Box 31, Folder 431)
  - Speeches and writings, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 432)
  - Flying and Popular Aviation. U.S. Army Air Forces Issue, 1941 (Box 31, Folder 433)
  - Speeches and writings, 1942-1946 (Box 31, Folder 434-437)
  - 49th annual manager's meeting of New York Life Insurance Company: speech, 1950 February 2 (Box 31, Folder 438)
  - Speeches and writings, 1950, 1953-1954 (Box 31, Folder 439)
  - Hill School: speech, 1951 (Box 31, Folder 440)
  - Speeches and writings, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 441)
    See also: box 26, folder 355
    See also: box 1, folder 9
    See also: box 1, folder 8
  - Speeches and writings, 1958-1959 (Box 31, Folder 442)
  - United States. National Policy Machinery Subcommittee: testimony, 1960 February 23 (Box 32, Folder 443)
  - Marshall Memorial: speech, 1960 August 10 (Box 32, Folder 444)
  - United States. Special Preparedness Subcommittee: testimony, 1962 January 16 (Box 32, Folder 445)
  - Anna Rosenberg Hoffman dinner: speech, 1964 April 16 (Box 32, Folder 446)
  - Sylvanus Thayer Award: speech, 1964 May 2 (Box 32, Folder 447)
  - Library dedication for George C. Marshall Research Foundation: speech, 1964 May 23 (Box 32, Folder 448)
    See also: box 9, folder 100
  - John Fitzgerald Kennedy Library: oral history (rough draft), 1964 (Box 32, Folder 449)
  - John Fitzgerald Kennedy Library: oral history (final draft), 1964-1965 (Box 32, Folder 450)
  - Speeches and writings, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 451)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission: testimony, 1966 February 1 (Box 32, Folder 452)
  - Federal Communications Commission: testimony, 1966 November 21 (Box 32, Folder 453)
  - Speeches and writings, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 454)
  - Interview, 1969 July 16 (Box 32, Folder 455)
  - Speeches and writings, 1970-1971 (Box 32, Folder 456)
  - United States. Blue Ribbon Defense Panel: testimony, 1970 April 28 (Box 32, Folder 457)
  - Columbia University Oral History Project: interview concerning Dwight Eisenhower and Hap Arnold, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 458)
    See also: box 14, folder 184
  - Office of the historian for secretary of defense: interview by Alfred Goldberg and Harry B. Yoshpe, 1974 May 13 (Box 32, Folder 459)
    See also: box 11, folder 117
  - "Some Qualities of Leadership," 1974
    See also: box 16, folder 213
  - Speeches and writings, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 460)
  - "The Civilian-Military Teamwork in Warfare", 1978 (Box 33, Folder 461)
  - Lovett Reading Room dedication for George C. Marshall Research Foundation: speech, 1981 May 7 (Box 33, Folder 462)
    See also: box 10, folder 109
  - Brown Brothers, Harriman & Co.: oral history, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 463)
  - Harry S. Truman Library: oral history, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 464)
  - Speeches, undated (Box 33, Folder 465)
  - "Design for Destruction", undated (Box 33, Folder 466)
  - "Economic Structure and Economic Policy, undated (Box 33, Folder 467)
  - "Spread of Socialism": notes, undated (Box 33, Folder 468)
  - Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System: testimony, undated (Box 33, Folder 469)
  - "Vanishing Wealth: A True Story About Investments", undated (Box 33, Folder 470)
- Oversize
  - George C. Marshall Research Library, 1973-1979 (Box 34, Folder 471)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: certificates, citations, honorary degrees, 1928-1974 (Box 34, Folder 472)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: newspapers and magazine clippings, 1951, 1952, undated (Box 34, Folder 473)
  - Lovett, Robert A.: photographs and portraits, undated (Box 34, Folder 474)
  - Photographs of friends and associates, 1943-1980, undated (Box 34, Folder 475-476)